Finding Aid for the Denna Frank Fleming Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings by D.F. Fleming - Articles and Reprints
  - “Are We Moving Toward Fascism?” in The Journal of Politics, February 1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - “Can We Keep Our Freedom?” July 1956, Vol. 63, no. 27
    - “The Danger of an Accidental World War”, September 7, 1958
    - “The Fifth World Order Study Conference Moves Toward Making Peace” May 3, 1959, Vol.66, no. 18
  - “Our Brink of War Diplomacy in the Formosa Strait” in The Western Political Quarterly, Vol. IX, no. 3, September, 1956. Also in The Western Political Quarterly: “ The Future of West Berlin” Vol. XIV, no. 1, part 1, March, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - What is Our Role in East Asia ?” Vol. Xviii, no. 1, March, 1965
    - “Vietnam and After”, Vol. XXI, no. 1, March 1968
  - “The Role of Europe in Current International Affairs” in Social Science, Vol. 33, no. 4, October, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Articles from The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science: (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - “Are We Moving toward Fortress America?” vol.312 (July, 1957), pp. 10 - 21
    - “Beyond the Cold War”, vol. 324 (July 1959), pp. 111 - 126
    - “The Broken Dialogue on Foreign Affairs”, Vol. 344 (November 1962), pp. 128 - 140
    - “The New Europe and the Cold War” Vol. 348 (July 1963), pp. 141 - 155
  - Articles from The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science: (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - “The Turn Towards Peace” vol. 351 (January 1964), pp. 157 - 169, 180
    - “Is Containment Moral?” vol. 362 (November 1965), pp. 18 - 27
    - “The Costs and Consequences of the Cold War” Vol. 366 (July 1966), pp. 127 - 138
  - “Can the Cold War Be Ended?” a background paper for use in the nationwide Program of Education and Action for Peace, June 1959 - June 1960, National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - “Was the Cold War Inevitable?” in International Studies Quarterly Journal of the Indian School of International Studies, New Delhi, Vol. II, no. 1, July 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “The Prospects for Peace” from United Asia, Bombay, India “ Can We Play God in Asia?” from The Progressive, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - “The Failure of Cold War I” in War/Peace Report, February 1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Reprints from New World Review: (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - “The USSR and World War III”, February 1967
    - “The Western Interventions in the Soviet Union, 1918 - 1920” Fall 1967
  - “Vietnam and the Crashing Dominoes” reprinted from New World Review, Summer 1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - “Can the Extinction of Man be Averted?” in Queen’s Quarterly, LXXVI, no. 3, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - “Can the Extinction of Man be Averted?” (with corrections notes, newspaper Articles), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - “Can We Escape from Containing China?” reprinted from The Western Political Quarterly, Vol. XXIV, No. 1, March 1971 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - “Can We Control our Militarism?” in Katallagete - Be Reconciled, Winter, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - “Do the Chinese Have the Answers?” 1972 (?) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - “What Can Our Bombs Accomplish?”, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - “Man on Earth: Can He Preserve His Environment?”, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - “Can We Create a Workable Economic Democracy?” (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - “Maddox and the Cold War” and accompanying articles concerning Maddox and the New York Times (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Reprints from The Nation (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - “Ways to Co-exist”, November 27, 1954
    - “When Did The Cold War Begin”, January 8, 1968
    - “Who Won the Cold War?”, April 15, 1968
    - “The Third World War”, April 6, 1970
    - “Our Conflict with the Soviets”, May 10, 1971
  - “Our Fifty Year Failure to Make Peace” in Canadian Dimension (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - “The Fall of China to Communism, 1927 - 1950” chapter from The Cold War, Vol. I with accompanying selected passages and reviews (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Writings by D.F. Fleming - Addresses, Lectures, Speeches
  - Address before the Seventh Conference on the Cause and Cure of War, Washington, D.C., January 20, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Four lectures in The Teachers College Journal, Vol. XVI, no. 4, March 1945 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - “Shall We Lose the Peace Again?”
    - “Can We Create a Workable Economic Democracy?”
    - “Ways Out of War”
    - “Steps Towards Peace”
  - Reprint of an Address “ The Soviet Union and Collective Security” in The Journal of Politics, Vol. 10, no. 1, February 1947 ( a paper read at the annual meeting of the Southern Political Science Associaton, Atlanta, Georgia, November 7, 1947) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - “ Can the United Nations Prevent World War III?” an address delivered before the Third Institute on World Affairs at Lynchburg College, Lynchburg, Virgina on, February 8, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - “Woodrow Wilson and Collective Security Today” an address delivered at Washington and Lee University, February 14, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - “The Future Belongs to Us” (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Writings by D.F. Fleming - Reviews
  - Reprinted from The Frontier, December 1964 review of three books: On Dealing with the Communist World by Amitar Etzioni Winning without War by Amitar Etzioni The American Problem: The Cold War in Perspective by Robert G. Wesson (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - American Images of Soviet Foreign Policy by William Welch in The Nation, May 10, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - History of the Cold War by Andre Fontaine in The Nation, April 6, 1970
  - In The Pastor: (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Containment or Liberation? by James Burnham, October 1953
    - Russia: What Next? by Isaac Deutscher, October 1953
    - The Kremlin VS. the People by Robert Magidoff, October 1953
    - The New Force by Ralph E. Lapp, June 1954
    - Report on the Atom by Gordon Dean, June 1954
- Writings by D.F. Fleming - Other
  - “Twenty five Assumptions Underlying the American End of the Cold War as They Developed from 1945 to 1952” (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - “What Does Russia Want?” An Estimate (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - “A Chronology of the Cold War” (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Photocopies of Fleming’s books from March 18, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Books published or republished, 1968 - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Suggested publishing procedure (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Writings by Others
  - Borda, Orlando Fals “Unfinished Revolutions in Latin America” a paper prepared for The National Conference The United States in a Revolutionary World AFSC Woodrow Wilson School, Princeton University, April 2,3,4, 1968, American Friends Service Committee (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Christensen, Frank A. Four Score Years - Fire Insurance Looks Ahead to Even Greater Service to the Public, an address delivered at the 80th Anniversary meeting of the National Board of Fire Underwriters, New York City, May 23, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Dyer, Dr. Gus W. - Notebook of Newspaper Articles for The Nashville Banner, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Gregg, Dr. Alan “The University in Relation to Medical Education”an address delivered at Neely Auditorium, Vanderbilt University, February 14, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Heywood, C. William and Wallace, Robert M. “Academic Freedom and Tenure: The University of South Florida” reprinted from AAUP Bulletin, Spring Issue, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Kennedy, John F. State of the Union Address, January 1961 in The Tennessean, January 31, 1961 with response by Walter Lippmann in The Chattanooga Times, February 1, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Southard, Blanche Rice, At One with Life, A Christmas Remembrance, 1970 Full Circle, A Christmas Remembrance, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Southard, Ken My New Eden: Ken’s Journey, A Christmas- Easter Remembrance, 1973 - 1974
  - Steel, Ronald “The X Article - 25 Years Later” in World View, September 1972 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Thomas, Elbert D.( Senator from Utah) “ Law Versus Chaos” University of Virginia, Evening address, July 12, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Writings by Others
  - Lectures I - VI - Legal matters (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lectures VII - XIV - Legal matters (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Publications
  - Department of State - The Trade Agreement with the United Kingdom, signed November 17, 1938, Vol. XIX, no. 477 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The German Problem, Roadblock to Disarmament - published by the Disarmament Committee of Washington, D.C. - Women Strike for Peace, c, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Soka Gakkai News: Promotion of Peace, Culture, and Education Through Buddhism June 1986, Vol. II, No. 208 (with accompanying letter) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - “Acorns” Gathered Under the Eucalyptus Trees at Benicia, California by the Enlisted Personnel, ordnance Supply School Benicia Arsenal, CA (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Canadian Dimension, June - July, Vol. 5, no. 5, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vanderbilt Gazette, No. 83, September 6, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Washington Spectator, vol. 9, No. 14, August 15, 1983
    - Map of Asia and the Pacific Naval Bases
- Subject Files
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Florida) - Correspondence and other materials (1) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Florida) - Correspondence and other materials (2) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Flordia) -Correspondence and other materials (3) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Florida) -Correspondence and other materials (4) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Florida) -Correspondence and other materials (5) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - D. F. Fleming - Johns Committee Affair, 1961 (University of South Florida) -Correspondence and other materials (6) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - James Maddox and his book The New Left and the Origins of the Cold War - Collection of articles, correspondence, and other materials (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - James Maddox and his book The New Left and the Origins of the Cold War - Collection of articles, correspondence, and other materials (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Political cartoons, 1926, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Materials on South East Asia - Cambodia, Vietnam, Laos (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Materials on South East Asia - Cambodia, Vietnam, Laos (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Vietnam - Viet Report an Emergency News Bulletin on Southeast Asian Affairs, August, September 1965 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Vietnam - newspaper articles (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Subject Files
  - Vietnam - Newspaper and journal articles and other materials (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam - Newspaper and journal articles and policy papers (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam - Newspaper and journal articles (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam - Newspaper and journal articles (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Photographs
  - D. F. Fleming - Portrait views - October 10, 1917(in uniform); October 1940, early 1950’s And n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - D. F. Fleming with John W. Vandercook, NBC at U.N. Security Council Meeting, NYC D. F. Fleming with Michell Demont, French Press and Information Officer, U. N. Security Council Meet D. F. Fleming and Gibson Parker, BBC Official, U.N. Security Council Coverage D. F. Fleming with Archibald MacKenzie, First Secretary British Delegation to U.N. Security Council during a special series of broadcasts over WSM from New York during the crisis over Iran in, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - D.F. Fleming in Delphi, Greece D.F. Fleming at Mr. Nehru’s address, Sapro House, April 5, 1960 - pictured also Princess Raj Kumati, Ambassador Elsworth Bunker, Dr. and Mrs. Emil Bogin (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Denna F. and Doris A. Fleming with unidentified friends (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Civil Liberties and Public Affairs Conference, May 26, 1951; unidentified group photo (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Family of Doris Anundsen Fleming: Eric Harold Anundsen (her father); Emily Brock Anundsen (her mother); Doris Anundsen with Pearl (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Adam, J. Louis – former student of Fleming, 1966 Kjold, H.; Adatci, Thomas, Madariaja (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - President F. D. Roosevelt with Secretary of State Henry L. Stimson, 1 - 9 - 33 Secretary of State Cordell Hull with Norman H. Davis, U.S. Ambassador at large (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified council meetings Buildings - The Old Secretariat; New “League” buildings - airview; Peace Palace (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Denna and Doris Fleming with friends and colleagues at a surprise party, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Slides
  - Fleming houses in Nashville, Tennessee on Sewanee Road and in Florida (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Western trip (late 1950’s) and Tucson (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Grand Canyon and photo of the Flemings (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Great Britain - Cambridge, Kensington Park, Henley-on-Thames, other (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Great Britain - Hampton Court, Kew Gardens, Kensington Park, Wales, and the Cotswolds (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - India (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - India (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - India (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - India - Kremlin (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Trip to Earl Kliner Gardens (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - San Gabriel, Jasper, Edmonton, unidentified (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Negatives (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Memorabilia
  - Postage stamps from letters (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Postage stamps from letters (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Postage stamps from letters (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Postage stamps from letters (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Memorabilia
  Certificate, State of Tennessee Governor’s Outstanding Tennessean Award, May 17, 1977
  Composite photographs of members of The Round Table, 1965
  High School Diploma of Doris Anundsen
  Notebook of Letters of tribute to D. F. Fleming on the occasion of a dinner in his honor on May 17, 1977, United Nations Association of Nashville at Belmont United Methodist Church
  Ordnance Supply School, Benicia, CA certificate, April 20, 1918
  Pocket size, Army cover, New Testament
  Photograph Camp Hancock, Georgia during WWI
  Keepsakes - Gloves, hair, watch, Phi Beta Kappa Pin, Phi Kappa Phi pin, “G” Mason lapel pin (square and compass)
  Diploma - Eastern Illinois State College Honorary Ph.D., June 5, 1949
  Certificate of Appreciation, Rotary Club of Huntington Park, CA, August 3, 1953
  United Nations Association of the United States of America, First Day Covers, 1971
- Denna Frank Fleming Recordings
  Boxes 25 and 26 of the Radio Recordings Collection housed offsite at 21 North, University Archives Annex of Vanderbilt University contain the following recordings of Fleming’s radio broadcasts for Station WSM in Nashville during the years 1940 -1945:
  Box 25 of the Radio Recordings Collection
- Denna Frank Fleming Recordings
  - May 29, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - June 1, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - June 12, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - June 19, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Economic Consequences of a German Victory/ Our Defense Problem in South America if Hitler Wins, June 26, 1940; June 27, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - America and the World Crisis, July 3, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - July 31, 1940/ August 7, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Our Decisive Moment/Some Illusions which Endanger Us, August 28, 1940, August 14, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - September 3, 1940/At Ease, Part 2, September 7, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Triple Alliance gives Us Notice/ Why Do We Have Conscription Again!, October 16, 1940, October 2, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - October 9, 1940/ Public Announcements (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - October 23, 1940/ October 30, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - November 20, 1940/November 27, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The President’s Call to Action/ All Aid to Britain Bill, January 15, 1941, January 8, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - February 5, 1941/William K. Anderson (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - February 19, 1941/February 26, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - March 5, 1941/ How Can the War be Won?, March 26, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - October 8, 1941/Riverboat Revels, October 4, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - June 10, 1942/ June 9, 1942 Blackout Test (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - December 2, 1942 Can We Win the Peace?/Grand Old Opry, Part 1, October 10, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - June 6, 1943/ What Kind of Peace Remains for Europe?, June 9, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - February 7, 1945 As the Big Three Meet/ Backstage Wife, February 7, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Box 26 of the Radio Recordings Collection
  - Denna Frank Fleming Series: How Can We Make Victory Stick? Sponsored by the Woodrow Wilson Foundation
  - Program 1, The German Plan for Beating Defeat/ Program 2, What War Criminals Shall be Punished? (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Program 3, Can Germany be Successfully Disarmed?/ Program 4, What Reparations Shall Germany Pay? (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Program 7, How Can Japan be Kept Harmless?/ Program 8, How Shall the Peace be Made? Two copies (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Program 9, Can the Senate Amend the Peace Treaties?/Program 10, What was Wrong with the League of Nations? (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Program 11, Can A Revived League of Nations Succeed?/Program 12, What Are the Main Issues? (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Program 13, Must we Have world Wars III and IV? (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Second Series: How Can We Make Victory Stick? Sponsored by the Woodrow Wilson Foundation
  - Program 1, Victory is Not Enough/ Program 2, why Did Japan Run Amuck? (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Program 3, Shall We Support the Japanese Emperor?/ Program 4, What Reforms in Japan are Fundamental? (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Program 5, Can China Achieve Democracy?/ Program 6, Can the Colonial Empires be Maintained? (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Program 7, Why Does Russia Distrust the West?/ Program 8, What Does Russia Want? (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Program 9, Can We Cooperate with Soviet Russia?/ Program 10, How Can Germany be Kept Peaceable? (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Program 11, Is Fascism a Continuing Danger?/ Program 12, Will the United Nations Organization Bring Peace? (Box 26, Folder 12)